TONIMARIE MORRIS

High-performing Sales Consultant and Account Manager turned Software Engineer

I develop clean and responsive applications optimized for exceptional user experiences. I leverage my analytical skills, positive attitude, and boundless curiosity to excel in fast-paced, metrics-driven environments.

SKILLS

JavaScript / HTML5 / CSS3 / SCSS / React / iQuery / Node / Express / MongoDB / PostgreSQL / Ruby on Rails

EXPERIENCE

Front End Software Engineer, Remote – Patrick Fritz for Delegate 2021

- Reverse engineered legacy website to implement critical updates.
- Maintained, monitored, and updated campaign website.
- Documented page views/increases.

Designer & Software Engineer, Remote – 4th Street Manor 2021

- Designed/developed a responsive website from scratch with no template.
- Chose lightweight tech stack (HTML/CSS/JavaScript) for ease of portability and maintainability.
- Ensured final site was accessible for screen readers while maintaining a modern aesthetic.

Coding Instructor, Remote – Bit by Bit Coding 2021

- Provided comprehensive JavaScript fundamental instruction to 8 Middle School students.
- Coordinated one-on-one and group instruction to meet students' individual learning needs.
- Led instruction on developer console and debugging.

<u>Additional Experience:</u> Account Manager – Star Valley Provisions (2017 - 2020) | Sales Associate/Repair Technician – Batteries Plus Bulbs (2016 - 2018) | Cellular Sales Representative (2006 - 2015) - nTelos Wireless, Verizon Wireless, US Cellular

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Udemy – Advanced CSS and Sass 2021

Udemy - 50 JavaScript Projects in 50 days 2021

Pluralsight – TypeScript: The Big Picture 2021

General Assembly, Remote – Full Stack Software Engineering Immersive Program 2020

Intensive 12-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of the following individual and group projects:

Lyrics Mobile: Utilized React Native to develop a mobile lyric search/list creation application.

Impulse: Developed a full-stack e-commerce app using MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.

Portfolio: Designed a mobile-first, responsive website with HTML5, CSS3, ¡Query, and Google Sheets API.

My Dictionary: Created a responsive dictionary app using React, SCSS, and Merriam-Webster's dictionary API.

Tunr: Built a full-stack playlist creation app with Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, and React.

Additional Education: Bluefield State College - Business Administration Classes

HONORS

- Highest Accessory Sales (2015) nTelos Wireless
- Top Salesperson in East Region (2012) Verizon Wireless

INTERESTS & COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT

- Blues Soup & 4th Street Manor Lead Singer
- Virginia Organizing Committee Member
- Waynesboro Democratic Committee Secretary